Welcome everybody ...to the session I hope you enjoy
...keynote think there were some really great an exciting use their about asher
...about windows ten so I have...unfortunate time flowed
I'm between you and your...the and today I'm going to talk
about inverting issues of...applications hosted
...measure ideas and has using virtual studio so just
...set expectations I'm not going to talk about how to trouble shoot you
...not coming up in...it's because...that's a common issues I'm also not
going to dive into like application insights or operational
...there's going to be talks this week about application insights and operational
insights so I'd highly advise you to go to those talks
...covering websites because there's another talk on friday about
website so this talk is really about cloud services vone?
And, ...a service applications running on...a service.
So, before I get started how many of you are aware of
...or heavy use as a diagnostics.
Okay, quite a few so how many of you have use the
...sdk two-point-five?
Ok,
so, today what I'm going to do in is session I'm going to talk about like.
Sorry.
Doesn't move...
So, I'm going to give you a brief introduction about typical issues we're seeing of
klout application and this is applicable to
...like cloud services as well as applications running on
...I'm also going to give you an overview of what kind of...provide
...virtual studio to help you troubleshooting a huge portion of this talk
will be focused on measure diagnostics because this is
our free framework and I'm going to talk about as a diagnostics and I'm going to show you
how to leverage that framework to implement instrumentation into
your application and then I also have a bunch of demos I have actually quite a lot of
...and I hope will work okay, so, what that let's get started?
So, one of the most common issues hra still see is a lot of
developers working on cloud services or building cloud services ...with their local
environment so...basically use the emulator to tester application and then
deploy the application to asher...all the sudden it doesn't work
and it's really hard for you to figure out why it's not working because it was working in the
emulator so we've done quite some work there but,
it's still a common issue that we're seeing for our support channels
so does that sound familiar to some of you okay so the next one is start of issues
with roles if you think about cloud services agile websites has pretty much replace
like cloud services web roles a lot of people...basically as a websites
...front-end now but there's a lot of implementations like io t,
for example, or processing...still running on worker rules and not supposed to be like that
and for that sometimes people install
custom software into the cloud service worker
role and then as a result of that if something goes wrong...boot-up time of
your application you get this nice little sign...as a role is...a cycling...
the role doesn't come up and you having issues actually knowing why I'm going to also
show you today how to trouble shoot those issues the next issues really performance issues I mean we all know
what...have seen that so you basically deploy application and it
feels like flow it is kind of slow sometimes it's really giving you
the performance you expect but then you put some load on it at the performance degrades
and you want to figure out why the last one is really logical issues
I know like developers never make any mistakes including myselfjust kidding
I'm a pm so, there is some logical issues in your application that
are really hard to like find the root cause of it and
it's really hard if you think about your application is now running...and you want troubleshooting and the next
...the last part is really if you use large or if you
it use instrumentation are tracing frameworks in your cold
it's really how can you actually look at the data because if you think about a scalable
...it produces a lot of data arrayed you probably
print-out like verbose messages and not only...so there's a lot of data you need to
consume we've also been hearing that
there's some problems with a I got way too many data
...service friends are way too many data I don't even know what
to where to start looking at so with that I'm going to switch the
slider chose basically where you can use in visual studio.
So, for difference between local environment measure it's really I know
it's subtle how many of you have to provide cloud services.
Okay, so, you may have not even notice it but when you hit the publish button
and virtual studio we bring up the activity windows but sometimes if
you go back to the build warnings window you see a build...that says hey
your deploying repackage...assembly that is not all measure so it's very subtle
and I just want to bring that to your attention that looking at build warnings offer you
...is a very good way or first step to diagnose
studies then obviously are logging
and tracing using actual diagnostics so implementing ...statements
there and using intelligence race how many of you have...telly trace?
How many of you have used...with...
Ok, so, intelligent...is basically and,
I'm going to show you that later how you can use intelligence with your...service
...a pretty good tool to do that so startup issues with roles
as a little bit trickier because you need to think about like to start of cycle overall so,
you can do something with logging in tracing if you're familiar with...role,
for example, you have an on start there which basically puts of your role so you can
portray statements in there and they would be caught but sometimes as I mentioned you want to
install software up-front like a real start of task and if that...
frozen error it's kinda hard to traces I'm going to show you today how to do this how you should properly
implement
like custom software your role in order to avoid that the next thing is really
...again because in telly trace is being...is being applied as a plug-in and
it's basically there in your machine on your virtual machine
...as your and can instrument like?
Your...worker process or uaw a is process.
And, the other tool it's very powerful is remote desktop
because everything that happens on the machine is obvious...to event lobsters also
log directory for...gas station that sits in the machine it also
knows if some processes failed...voting and then you can basically go in there and, identify
...performance issues logging in tracing again
arrow diagnostics visual studio profiler and application...so
...the talk victors giving three-week...a great tool or...a great service I should
say for analyzing performance issues logical issues again,
logging in tracing measure diagnostics we have remote debugging how many of, you know,
about our motive avi functionality okay quite of...so you can actually do park
your cloud service although we don't advice to do that or we don't recommend to do that and production
...and then again application
insights so as you can see those are like really the typical issues we
run into in cloud services and there is one common
...like you can catch most of them for logging
in tracing and logging in tracing we really try to embrace it and take it to the next
level because we've seen customers that started like they put in a
...statement here tray statement...and the service grows and
grows organically or it's been like very successful and all the sudden you're there and you don't
have to proper tracing in it and you basically need to rewrite it or add...
tracing kind of capabilities we deployed so on so forth so that's why I'm going
to focus most of this talk on really
...diagnostics because it's the framework the free framework for logging and
tracing and measure so what allows you to do is.
You can first and foremost implement application logging
in tracing so if you're used to traced trays...traced trays information
using system diagnostics name space you can still use that but if you want
to go like one step further and you embrace semantic logging, for example, or events
...gw events source this is also going to be cog or being used
or I should say the...diagnostics
...will also collect you tw traces and put them in the
...so how many of you are aware of each w events...
Okay, so, besides like your application logging in tracing windows
are diagnostics or measure diagnostics gives you another could capabilities because it also
monitors event locks on your virtual machine so-if you have a cloud services
basically virtual machine on...use all on your ideas machine and it captures the
...like your typical...logs or...failed request locks it captures the performance
...in also can deal with custom performance connors that you add to
your application and I'm going to show you how to do this?
...collects crash dumps.
It can collect custom locks and custom
lots of something that you would set up if you want to install additional software on of...role,
for example, and, it collects...infrastructure
...so if you look at this is really a very...plead like
free framework for getting diagnostics information out of
you system the other thing is if you think about like a rich tracing and
...strategy you really want to tested out locally so
in agile diagnostics we also have on premisesor I should say
...local...poured through the emulator you can paisley...
portray statements and your code you hit the emulator you see what...coders basically printing
out or tray statements of printing out that's actually a very good way of testing
your diagnostics because sometimes people think about diagnostics
...just production no but for a really good diagnostic
strategy you want to tested out so you can do this locally with the emulator.
how does this h and I was talking about actually gets applied and the reason
I was asking before whether someone is using address decay two-point-five is
in two-point-five you made a big switch we actually moved to an extension
model that means if you think about an average extension there's a piece of
...software sitting somewhere in
the cloud and this waiting for command so what's happening here is an
this is applicable for infrastructures a service...as well as for cloud services
I should say so you get your already and then you want
enable diagnostics and you can do it from any kline you can do it from
herschel studio you can do it from the portland you can to through our shells so as
an automation step what's happening then is the command or the
api is called the extensions store and say hey I want to enable
...diagnostics on a particular machine then
...is being pulled down and...being applied?
The good thing about it's really.
Very dynamics so you can apply the extension at any time before
like before sdk two-point-five in sdk two-point-four you always
had to package dh and,...move...the appnow we basically
...that dependency away so...really flexible of doing that.
And, when you want to applied the other thing is the extension
itself takes a configurations so the truth of your configuration for
...diagnostics is really just one configuration file before they were
also like api to configure diagnostics which led to a lot of confusion which one as
a truth like is...configuration fide a declarative one or is it like the
declarative one at the imperative one in the code so this is
all been gone away or it's all gone away...just one truth
is one extension and one configuration so there was a lot of talk let's switch to the first demo?
So, in here I have.
Meeting the theme of today I
...very so I have a very simple application what is actually
...let me just...through it quickly it's a worker role that wholeness over in
uncut tama it's basically also web and point and,
then the webendpoint already api get some messages sensor data
it's basically mimicking like and io t scenario so if I go
...controller here what's happening is like any client can basically
...message and poet sensor data in it and it starts processing
the data and then it.
Disconnect from measure.
Try one more time.
Now you don't think so.
Now...coming up.
...thing is I have a local copy but I might need to switch level.
All right let's...
All right.
I was expecting having trouble finding the right deployed service because I have
some many but not that I can connect okay so we're back up again so bottom line is
...it's basically at a web...chosen a worker role and that gets messages from
...point so if I go to the message
here stories synthesis where all the magic happens if I look at
it I basically receive the...information
...the central sensor information and all the data is being put into a...
cash while I'm doing that here I have a bunch of tray statements in my code like,
for example, lunch tracing or I'm putting out trace information statements about
what the information is that I stored I'm also going to put out like trace information about the
sends or id so on so forth so it's very typical for developers to put that type of
code...so let me show you now the as a diagnostics part
of it so first if I go to the role
of I...in here and that's what we call the role designer and in here I have my
service configuration and you may know that and go to all configuration and here I have
...enable diagnostics a button so by default if you create a new
cloud service project or if you start from another one by default we always turn on
as a diagnostics so that basically means when you use social studio to publish will
apply the ext that's the very first thing that we apply so then in the year.
I have this nice little dialogue that says okay this is what
you can configuring measure diagnostics and think about what I was talking before
...I was talking about before like what can you do
...diagnostics this is basically the dialogue that's a
ui over and over and the xml over the configuration file so we thought we make it
really easy for you to do this so in the application logs here is ...application locks
and application locks is really your traced...star right so everything that goes
through the trace listener is being locked into this application
locks.
By default we only set it to errors because as I mentioned
...it on by default so we don't want you to deploy your as
...your service to...all the sudden nothing start spitting out data because you're tray
statements are being transferred to storage in here you can also.
To windows event
locks performance counters so as you can see here I have custom performance
...code which is basically get
the device request get sensor data regress
...total device regress so on so forth so I can configure my custom performance
connors infrastructure logs log directories it by default
...the...and...request locks et w and,
I'm going to talk about each w later and...crashed...you can...crash dumps that you want to
collective something goes wrong and here we have like the most important services
the first one is really...that the host process for wthree w
...and the second one is remediation work
...process so something goes in the wrong in their and uni able
...will catch...so that's the first part of the second part is maybe
it's worth pointing out if you don't provide a storage
...in here because as you can see there is aprovide
storage account information if you don't provide one in here.
Will take the storage account that you used to publish the package too so because
as a diagnostics needs to get the data of the...stores it in a storage account
and what we do is if you don't have enabled we basically uses
storage accounted useful publish why are we doing that is think back when
I was saying a lot of people do something in the emulator and then it doesn't work and
...that's basically your first in a loop test we don't expect you to use
social students deploy to productions...but usually goes into a...tasks
...in manager so but then you have at least diagnostics turned on and you could see what's
going on so let's look at the last piece of how diagnostics as wired
...so in app dot com fake or in a web dot
com fake we have the actual diagnostics...we
...by default as well and this is the reference to it...it's here?
So, think about by default inspired...the app conflict for web roles of for
...roles the web dot com fake for web roles has the diagnostics
...set up the configured by default to collect
errors and if you don't provide a storage account...use the storage account
...you useful publish so.
Let's assume undone I have
...tracing and I want to see how it works right because I really want to see how to messages
come out let's fire up.
So, I should say this is visual studio twenty fifteen rc and
in cst...two-point-six that we will released this week unfortunately of
...on this now it's probably going to crash.
All right let's try it again.
So,...the output window I'm getting like some information that sets might measure
...working so on so forth so you get some tracing statements in the output
...but there's also.
...emulator ui.
Which is here and if I open it up?
This one I see my deployed
rock-and-roll instance and I see all the output so what I'm going to do now is.
I have written...nice little simulator app that thing basically simulates a bunch of devices and palms a
bunch of messages internet service now so I'm going okay so it's connecting to the
endpoint and it's putting the messages
into my service so now if I can you guys see that okay.
So, now if we look at it I get all the tray statements that I have
...my...and basically says...the sensor data like the pressured
...temperature sensor idea so on so forth so that's...should give you an
idea how you can actually use the local experience to test
your diagnostics features like...traced...trays our information.
So, the other thing is let's stop debugging here.
Let's go to the deployment let's say I'm done I tested my
local experience I have my trace statements ic everything is working as a one so,
what I want to do now is?
I want to...service let me just go in here.
Corrupting...
What I'm doing here is...I just point?
Little application internet service.
Then I'm going...again
...fast so the way I would publish it I assume you all have seen...
to publisher cloud service but I go through it very quickly so I would go on.
...service.
...publish and...just go in here.
Starts here I pick my and pick my subscription I see my different slots that I want to have an
in I pick my configuration picked environment and I basically
...publish so,
once a services published you're now in that situation
that was working locally you had your tray statements working
...now you want to see what's happening in your life service so
for that let's switch over to server explorer and.
Drill into the service.
this is my simple io t service here I have my staging node.
And, here I have my role so under role itself I could say
few diagnostics data which would basically do the following like if you have a
role of multiple instances you would get
an aggregated view of your diagnostics data for that particular roles
...gather all the data all the errors
from all the instances because I only have one instance here.
I just say here few diagnostics data and.
What's happening now is it's basically reaching out treasure and says hey
...diagnostics...a storage accounted I have defined before.
And, again, that should bring up.
The what we call diagnostic summary...so this is the diagnostic summary of in
...and not getting confused this is not meant to be like your
diagnostics your for production system because it wouldn't scale right
this is really meant to be like hey I've done might development locally
...published a to adj or something went wrong I want to cna or
...want to see my locks and this is really what of needs so in here I have a.
What I've done is in the service that are
published just made a tiny little tweak and every I think every nine...sense
and errorjust to show you what it does so if there's an error because
...page only shows your errors to begin with right because we don't want
to have like you have to deal of all the data that's in there because as you see there's a lot of
...oggi as well so this one here gives you an
adj application log error and if you look at it you can hover over...and says
...five did not submit any data so for us developer
...now in a positions so you've tested locally you...treasure
something went wrong you go to the summary page and then in the summary page all the errors
...listed right away so if you happen to have many of those errors?
We also have
...to see as we because that like that summary page doesn't have
great filtering capabilities but we understand a lot of people use xcel for it so
we implemented a button you can open-ended...pulls out all the data from that table into
...and you can use
excel to analyzer issues there the other thing maybe to talk about you have event...and things like
that so everything looks good the last thing I want to point out here is.
Let's say for some reason I head-on checked that enable diagnostics checkbooks
in my project and now I want to chairs or now I want to collect
...data I can got I can just go to server
explore and in year I have update diagnostics if it wasn't
...say enable diagnostics and if I go to update diagnostics I
...get the same dialogue that I had locally and I can basically just
apply...settings so, for example, I could say here my application lot,
you know, what I not only want to see my errors I really want to see like
the verbose information and me going to...back...what's happening is all your
locks are being basically transferred into the storage account any confusion?
Does that make sense of...ok so?
Let's switch back to...
this was really a very-high-level tour of diagnostics all you take of a should be really
okay if I use system dot diagnostics
...super easy everything is wired...for me right I can tweak it so
...studio really has you has your...I should say so let's
talk about the next issue which is start of issues so how many
of you have seen that light nice little picture down there where...role...a cycling state?
Many if you so before I'm
going to show you how to or before I'm going to tell you how you could actually like diagnose
it probably going to show you how you should do it right basically
installing software right so, we had customers I talked to
a customer recently who actually...on graphics rendering and what they do is
they basically put the wrong times components on worker...because this
been of like massive amount of work rules to do this graphics rendering and they were
really like having issues with those diagnostics startups things because some
roles just didn't come up so what we've done is we sat down with our
support team who actually was a great help in showing how to diagnose it but we also thought
okay what's actually a good way of avoiding that if you want to put
another software on it and really the way to do it is you should
setup your cloud service so that the logging of a startup
...that install something is
therefore use when you could just see it and I'm going to show you that's
the next demo I'm going to show you how to do this in a second?
So, if those steps those are very-high-level steps you need to add a local storage element
to-you...daffodil you also need to create an environment variable
that actually contains to have tree...directory and then the last
of is you need to tell actor.
To basically collect the...from that directory and
transferred into storage it's a very.
Simple three-star rule
and I can show you how to do this and I think today we're also going to have a blog announcement it goes
...that shows executives if that didn't help.
The steps you can do in order to diagonal startup...
Again,
check your build warning because sometimes start of tasks are due to missing assembly
references...virtual studio and even if you don't use it for
employment you can use the cs pacman right because the cs pacman would also show you a
difference as the output the other thing is what you need to do next...should do is you already
p into the machine the good thing about already but he now is.
The virtual studio...still package it as a plug-in so you need to...
studio but if you have forgotten to do it or you didn't want to do it like
to portal now...and extension as well so you can just enable remote desktop one-year-olds at
any time and then you basically go into your into your instance you
check the windows of unlocks usually it's a very good source of information especially if something
...wrong.
Then you can check...w a host bootstrap...in the
...resources directory so this is basically like the whole rules set up the
role start-up because what's happening is there's an h and ron's to cook is a
...and communicates with the whole stage and then it says hey I have it
gets the information I have three startup tasks...to run...and then would actually show you
...it when it breaks down and then if that...have you can go to the app runtime locks
so usually this is really the only thing what you need to do in order to get a
rich set of information and this is I would say nine-out-of-ten cases,
you know, why your role cycling now if you do this however there
is like this one case that the log stone to anything and
your only chance really there right now as of now is you need to
...install...and, attach it to the...or a worker dot actually processes
and really give up those processes another option is if you have
...telly trays and you can redeployment
you can try before you install something on your machine you can try enabling
in telly trays in your cloud service project and redeployment
servers and toiletries enabled because...trees will also monitored
...process and...the on start method but it
won't catch like things that happened way before so installing software?
So, let me show you how to do start of locking for
...need to switch machines now going in here.
And, let's start a new visual studio on.
Okay, because...crashed into this.
in here this is a visual studio project it only has a worker role and if you look at the
worker role itself doesn't do anything and.
What...worker role really does is I basically use it as a
transport object to install dot net four-point-five point-two?
Because we currently
don support four-point-five point-two...os so you with the to install it and I thought
that's a really good opportunity to show you how to install dot net four-point-five
...tool on a cloud service...and show you how
to how to implement proper logging so.
In here the first step I need to do is I go in here in my siesta
And, as I mentioned I add the local resources here I call
it local storage install locks and I give it like a size whatever you expect in that case
it's five megabytes then I'm going to set over...task
here and, I say okay in that startup task executed install comment
and install comments basically scripted installs dot net framework four-point-five point-two run
it elevated and tossed of a simple.
And, then I basically have environment variable
depth sets the path to install locks and,
here's the path that we actually
...put the locks...so this is the very first step now
what happened when I add that I should highlighted when I add this piece too.
When I add this piece to my seo staff?
Once the service starts provisioning
it's being told hey I need a local resources storage when you start
exes when you start of execute that command and then also use
that directory for...so that point you're pretty good shape if
you're script rights to...directory what's not happening at
...point is you your errors are not being transferred into
storage of point because...diagnostics doesn't know about it so to make
agile diagnostics aware of it you go in here to the.
To the role itself but this time you cannot use.
The nicely ui because honestly we don't have support for
...you need to go to the xml.
And, any xml...directories.
Element and it has the iso
locks and failed request logs and what you do in air is you basically?
...you add a new data source and
the directory configuration and say okay my directory configuration has to
name contain as a container name and that's basically container name that will show of
an blob storage.
And, then the local resource...install...and
then the last step here is you basically just add the dot net framework installer
and...command command script to your role so in that
...command script you see thatrewriting...messages.
To...directory so this is pretty much and then once you have
deployed the service.
When you see is you go in here?
You go to your cloud service.
And, going here.
So, I'm going to go to my cloud service this is a cloud service that I install
...here you can also say if you
diagnostics data again so it's opening up the diagnostics data for this cloud service.
If I go to the directory list of
...right because I as...failed regress...or this one is being transferred
...blogs you get this nice little thing here and remembered
...install was my container name and I can basically click on it.
It's getting ...data here net installer and then I have my startup
tasks in the...task...so this
is really the proper way if you want to install software on a
role whether it's a web or worker role to implement logging because as I've seen
is now something goes wrong during your...process you have a very convenient
...to reach those locks if that's not the case you need to go through all that hassle that I showed
you before so that's why...highly advise you to do this again we...blog about that so
you can basically tried yourself and it's really good way to avoid start of issues.
All right so let's step back to...
Ok, so, now we've talked about how
measure diagnostics a set of inertial studio how to use...trace cloth and
how to basically enable logging for start of issues?
So, for those of you are familiar with each...
Event source that's another way of implementing logging
in the way we think about it is the system diagnostics
the trace class is really good for scenarios
where you have like I'd say a predictable size of data coming
and coming in or when, you know, you don't have a
lot of super-high scale on your on your machine or on your service so,
...the more you go into...scale-up art direction
...more data is getting produce your problem you really want to get some structure in your
locks because if you look at...the messages of traced trays information
...traced...star it really just takes a string
right so everything is pond out as a string you get an object because you use a method that says it's an error
...but that's pretty much about it
you could do-it-yourself by implementing keywords but then you have to do a lot of string parsing a lot of
strain combination so what you really want to do than is you want to get some structure
...your logging in a way to do this is a using...w events...so,
you tw events
...only like a good way to implement structure logging but it's also?
Really designed for high scale so anything that wrongs like what
scot-free was mentioning this morning like service fabric our
super hyper scale framework uses...to
...events so that goes along...we...pretty much everyone to switch
...gw events...and I'll show you...give you an example why so, it's designed for high
scale but more importantly all the operating system components on a windows system
...using it so now think about
your run multiple processes and multiple services on your virtual
...on your machine on your virtual machine or your instance you just want to have one
...where you get your
tray statements from because eventually you could even correlate those events and this is what
...tw events oars gives you a as an offering so with two-point-five
...the address decay two-point-five.
We started supporting
...w when...in measure diagnostics and.
This is actually something we've been working on to get in with the cat team
for a while because our cat team custom architecture customer
...date basically look after all the high skills services and we figured okay traced
...information or
...error only get to a certain point but you really want to have...gw so, we
started partnering with the actual diagnostics teams so we took some ownership of the
agents we have a very close collaboration together and now we have each w supporting
the continue...building on that so let me show you what that means free...
And, let's switch back to this machine...
Close...is one.
So, this is our familiar.
Application here the device controller I was using nothing has changed.
Except now I have a new...
If I go to class
it derives or usesmicrosoft diagnostics tracing.
And, then it has an event...derives from events...and has
...attribute in that case because it's my simple io t gateway
...just I I've just given at the name microsoft build io...gateway but,
you'll soon see ready advantages so the first thing what I'm going to do is I'm going to
define some keywords here and say okay because I want to filter
to data later on I say I know a bunch of keywords that I need to look offer have requests
aiff information I have errors and I have some sensor information so that's what I define
...very first step the second step is?
I implement so-called events in
...as you can seeI just have...info method and it has an attribute and
it's to event because it's my very first event I give it an idea of one
...the level is...most
of working awesome so the level is event level informational
but even here you can see I can even set a channel event channel operational.
And, then if I go.
Now if I go further down after keywords and say keyword
...so if I look at my code and I can implement like many
events like that admittedly this is like more effort you need to put it
in your development up-front and it seems to be really cumbersome but
trust me as soon as you go to scale this is worth it and you can see papers from
...team leveraging that because we really embrace that so let's see how
a method ...implementer let's go to device store.
In here I have.
Is...some all-knowing works again so in here typical saying I'm going
to basically I reference I'm going to use longer using statement and...referencing
And, then down here.
Remember I had before I had the law traced trace information and
then I put some sensor id in there but this is basically the decrepit
...of it but it becomes more obvious if I'm going to do this if I'm going to go to the next one so
here's the entries been created.
Now if I would use or if I were to use traced
odp trays information I had to do bunch of string combination
...it because I would be to say hey this...this was a pressure
...the temperature right so on so forth so in the
year as a developer I just need to know hey I created...entry and
the signature of the method tells me what I need to put in there if I go to this definition.
Nope, it's got to definition.
Okay.
So, if I go to the definition here.
I can see it it's also it has the of...ninety-seven lovely
...informational channel operational info and I basically do all
the string concatenation and stuff like that and methods signature
so you code is really clean and all the...work is being done in your logging...so.
Let's try it again I'm going to run is now locally again and
just to show you what the outcome of those trace messages
and for that I'm going to go.
Back here.
...grab my local.
...a start my service.
Okay, I'm going to...the local...here.
See it's working.
Khatami app...messages in there.
...to the local one and then.
To my storage account I have my development storage which is basically my local
storage emulator and that mimics the behavior of your storage
account and production so you would see exactly same thing and,
that's true for traced trace information as well as for...tw events
so if I go to the tables emir I see I have a new table which is
...rat io...gateway and here's...table because I still have some
...statements and year but if I go to...gateway table.
You'll see that I have a way richer set of information and
everything is very well structured and I can even like look for task
names so I could have or I have really rich filtering capabilities the other thing I want to
point out is how do I enable that so what I've done in
here is in my local setting of entry dw tab and
...here I basically just said my event source to microsoft build io
...gateway...was the name and the attribute of my class.
then I gave it a name how we chose should show up in the storage location which is imc gateway.
And, then basically shows up in your local emulator
likely development environment as well as in your storage account if you have to service
deployed so this is a really, really good way so, now switching gears a little
...case...something funny here.
Let's go to the simulator and.
...bob to message...to let's say or let's say we simulate like
fifteen hundred devices because think about I tested locally and now I want to
...production that's again my scenario that I had before and now I
have seen okay it's working now I want to tested and production
...deployed my service ies save that because it's taking like ten minutes and then I'm going to
have my simulator fire up I just need to change.
...going here.
Can go into the open...and file explore?
...just to make sure I have to write url in their nope of course not.
Come back here taking this service.
That's basically my deployed service that now has e w events
...and naught traced...statements...
And, I run it...
So, this is now like pumping fifteen hundred method
...a simulating fifteen hundred devices but now you may
...when we may get a problem
...because this is just fifteen hundred devices and it you see how
many like data it's basically producing within a very short period of time
...constraint now is getting to how do I if you to
data how can I actually make sense out of the data because I'm getting so much data now into my system
how can I do that so again we partnered with the catchy and,
we basically build a connector to...
Anyone heard about elk.
So, it's basically a elastic search
...stash and keep on up so it's an open-source framework built by
elastic...thing that has that can take huge amounts of data and basically
visualizing so we partnered with them as an intermediate solution and let me show you
Going back while this thing is producing it.
Back here.
And, I go to my dashboard nsa like the...
what's happening here is as you can see there's a very rich visualization opportunity now I don't want
to go...much into detail what the alex...and what you can
do think the only message that I want to bring a crosses yes,
we've heard you...working on it to make rad really
scalable as a first app what we're doing is we partnering or we
basically build a connector to alec so that you can use out for your visualization and,
then as a second step we're going to work on the on the agent itself to make the throughput of the
agent collects data even faster so that's the next...and that's coming shortly often
build so, let's look at us I think you're a little bit because?
It's very easy and we'll...of them get
...soon after the session.
If I go in here.
...you get is basically a download from a ripple and we have a bunch of
sample scripts for you so you don't need to do much...here
...basically download the...on your local machine this is all you get in
here you get like you can set up fancy advanced elastic search clusters or you can
just play around with it we have simple.
Sample alec instance, for example,
and, all you need to do is you basically go in here you go to dr
...stash configuration and you
...and then this is all provided to you all you need to do...is
...stash configuration is you need to...to your storage
...diagnostics data ends up and then you basically...partial script.
That's in thing and spins of an instance where you and you can
...so it's a very powerful tool and I think why I wanted
to share with you is okay we keep investing in it we heard you that we need to work on
this and this is one solution another one which is along those lines don't get
...like we also microsoft offers great services like that like application insights again
there's a great session about it and avocation insights goes a little bit further even with like teller
...and things like that but if you're used to reallocate stacked that's probably also
a good solution ok all right let me switch back.
Now we've seen basically I hope I've shown you and I've
proven you that like okay as diagnostics for smaller applications that
...run hyper scale visual studio pro is a really great tool to get you started as a
diagnostics...recreate from framework to use and,
then I went like a little bit further and said okay this is how it could look like if you go
at scale and I was the last part and you could use, for example,
alec or any other third-party tool that actually is
...the data so just to summarize on your diagnostics part
the benefits are really it's a free framework so, you can dh...the
hn wrongs on as your ideas and paths so I'm going to get to the
...part in a second because I haven't talked a lot about ins and that's the beauty about
as a diagnostics it's exactly the same thing and that's the beauty of having
...extension so everything I've shown you how to
configured how to get the data from a storage account everything
is applicable you could even use what I've just shown...the end that you can connect your
...stash plug-in that search account for you could even do that...that's a really great
tool so...by default wired of inertial studio and as
a diagnostics obviously as many third-party tools that support the entire thing.
So, considerations there is a catch though as I mentioned so
the problem is currently in this version of...diagnostics it's.
Because it's a it's tightly coupled to agile tables
...so all the data you collect this being reading...as a tables
...actually...constrained by
the input characteristic of as a tables as well as for
...so there's some limits...you can hit and
...can thing if you have a supra hyper scale system that limit will be reach
or can be reached so there's one catch that's the other thing I said we're working on like making
that collection better allowing you've directly from the agent to put the data into
...into otherlike repositories?
So, this is really it I showed youon dl let's talk about let's spend
a lost three minutes to talk about virtual machines on
...as I mentioned I haven't talked about virtual machines at all the reason is it's really
the same implementation you have an extension model repackage the same...and
uses the...configuration file and uses as...a storage
or storing data so everything I was talking about like the last forty five minutes
as applicable to iso as well let's switch to the last move todayand, then
so switch over here and open.
This one because I really want to show you something cools I think so this here is
a...application and the guesswork application
very famous it's almost like fabric so, what does the web front-end runs on
...virtual machine on...and its using a worker role in a...but,
what I'm doing in here as well as if you go to?
Home controller I'm using events...go to events
first definition and here logging all my data so now the first issue.
That we're having is in a cloud service world.
I have to is nys emulator it can actually tested I can test my events source data
...here...until now I couldn't but I'm going to show you
a trick we haven't fully integrated...yet but there is a way so let's.
Let's fire up to guesswork.
Of course use ...
The district bring it up and...brings it up.
Let me show you something scot-free announce like service fabric this morning obviously
...also building truly for it and one part of
the tooling is you see here it's called service fabric clusters so we have a node
...here and we will have tooling...that node comes something really,
really great and I don't have a service fabric application whatsoever but I can go in here and say
few diagnostics events so now if you diagnostics event we basically have a
local et w
...that you can use for any project because if I'm going to go in here and say configure
ic mike my events sources...and now.
If I go to my guest book.
And, I go to my guesswork and save or as
...samoa.
I upload...
...good pictures to use sign guess...
And, go back here you see those traces are being written out in real-time.
So, recruit part here is now you see you can see because I instrumented my code using
events...on of web sided will go into...measure virtual machine and
now you can see okay what happened exactly and you get the structured information
that I was talking about before and you can even filter for it and you can see
things like from nail and sly search so it's a really,
really good tool and I want to show you that the next thing.
It's what you would need to do in order
to make diagnostics work now on adrg.
...virtual machine is you need to at the.
The trace listener remember I showed you...file with...trace listen for an app configure
web dot com fake it's obviously not there because we don't know what kind
of project your creating so if you just create a simple project that project doesn't know about
...diagnostics whatsoever so you would need to go in here.
In your ...fake and you need needed to maybe
have it you would need to add your trace...here and you can just copy it an any reference
...assembly and then you publisher to the virtual machine doesn't make sense so,
let me just show you one more thing and
then and promotional this is the web this is the virtual machine
at hosts the website that I was just showing you the way to enable diagnostics
...of virtual studio is you can go to the configuration part.
And, then we have to is configuration page in...
I have extensions and you can basically grab the.
Windows monitoring agent for diagnostics you
add it and what's happening is well...you get exactly the same
dialogue now you could basically just pointed to...
You could basically pointed to a storage account any n.
...it let's go
...this one so I have my everything set up I would need to add my
...source here as I showed you before and then basically you hit
okay and then you updated...and then your diagnostics
is wired up here so this is exactly the same basically the same familiar
tool same familiar technologies for paths as well as ys?
And, then a few in part it's.
We don't have like a nice summary page reviewing like we have four...because we don't know which storage
...you putting it into...basically need to look up yourself so,
with that because we'reI really don't want to stand in a way of your.
Of your lunch so, just let-meskip forward quickly the flights.
So,...couple other things like as I mentioned application...great
...analytics diagnostics rufus great dashboards there's going to be a great session
on friday and I highly encourage you to go there because it's very insightful and,
see what...this teams up to in
...they've done really great job there then there's operational...which is also ...
blocks into as your diagnostics and all that stuff that I've shown you but currently
read-only transfer state over from windows event locks and rad windows event
...tables so basically it doesn't take your et
w data and things like that but they're working on it as...just one to keep that in mind those are the
...services that we provide recreate so as a summary.
I hope I showed universal studio tools that are available to trouble shoot
...an ins I notice talk...mainly focusing on
...diagnostics but we truly believe if you have a good instrumentation story
in your code you role avoid a lot of those pitfalls and troubleshooting
your service once the service scales...get three successful I also give you a deeper
...outlook what's coming with like we having
an elk integration will agree integrate more...own services will improve
the agent so the last part is there a bunch of sessions and I mention some of
them throughout my session already there is a session today it surviving five gcses
architect...websites for rapid growth for...during that session
it's very interesting if you're interested in like larger-scale environments then micros
...a lessons from scale building applications for measure it's also very interesting goes
along those lines the mike morton is going to talk about what's new for developers and
virtual story and address decay tomorrow so he's
going to give you an overview of everything some of the stuff that I've showed you is a repeat but,
he's going to give you a diagnostics overviews
going show you are docket tooling and all that type of stuff really great session and then there's
this application inside session fasten powerful diagnostics friday highly encourage you to
...historical debugging and telly trays and then the last one was
the troubleshooting applications on measure apps service that's basically the website part
so there are two pointers learn more about...that's the release
...we should have released by now literally or if not then tomorrow.
And, as your diagnostics and the alec stack what we've done there that's basically the...to repo if
you're interested ...that I really thank you for coming here I hope it...for you and you
session and if you have any questions regarding the topic that we didn't cover or
we haven't covered like how do I do entirely trays how do I do this debugging stuff I
just find meta booth more than happy to talk to-you about that and that ...your build?